<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>job doc | Digital space of K. Bret Staudt Willet</title>
    <link>http://bretsw.com/tag/job-doc/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://bretsw.com/tag/job-doc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>job doc</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://bretsw.com/media/icon_hu327cdc32eb61737bbb22c3db2388dbf1_47180_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>job doc</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/tag/job-doc/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Career Reflection</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/career-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/career-reflection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve applied for a handful of academic jobs in the past six months, as many tenure track faculty positions as I could imagine fitting my experiences and skills. In the present higher-education-during-COVID-19 reality, that has amounted to six jobs to apply to (with hopefully more posted in the coming weeks). Three of those I applied to have since been removed from consideration by university-wide hiring freezes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work is hard to come by nearly everywhere these days, giving me cause to pause and reflect on my professional journey to date. I’ve been thinking quite a bit about what comes next after I defend my dissertation and graduate in the coming months, perhaps three, certainly no more than nine months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-work&#34;&gt;My Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I reflect on my career arc, I characterize my work in one summary statement: &lt;strong&gt;I lead communities for the common good into the future.&lt;/strong&gt; I explain what I mean in the following sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;leading&#34;&gt;Leading&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I lead in a variety of ways. I generally consider my &lt;strong&gt;leading&lt;/strong&gt; to be teaching, and my &lt;strong&gt;teaching&lt;/strong&gt; to be leading. I also lead by developing research to advance general understanding of a topic. And I lead in an entrepreneurial sense, forming teams and helping them advance toward a goal. In each of these areas, my primary leadership goal is to increase the &lt;em&gt;agency&lt;/em&gt; of those I work with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;communities&#34;&gt;Communities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I study, and have increased general understanding of, groups of people in a variety of ways. I have framed my research in terms of affinity spaces, learning networks, and communities of practice. I have engaged in best practices of online teaching and learning. And I have established virtual teams and built distributed organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-the-common-good&#34;&gt;For the Common Good&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I produce not just solutions to problems, but &lt;em&gt;generalizable knowledge&lt;/em&gt; that may help others with similar problems in their own distinct contexts. In addition to sharing this knowledge, I share the process. I conduct my work following the principles of &lt;em&gt;open science&lt;/em&gt;, such as making my datasets and coding scripts publicly available whenever possible. The values of diversity, equity, and inclusion shape all the work I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;into-the-future&#34;&gt;Into the Future&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My vision of the future is neither utopian nor dystopian. I do not believe technology will save humanity nor destroy us. Instead, I believe what we do with technology matters. We should not simply try to replicate traditional approaches online or with technological support. New modalities require their own consideration. We should lead with asking &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;, clearly defining the problems we intend to solve. This means understanding our users, their contexts, and larger societal and systemic realities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-skills&#34;&gt;My Skills&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-big-four&#34;&gt;The big four:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connecting (with) people.&lt;/strong&gt; I’m best at connecting with people and connecting them with each other.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asking great questions.&lt;/strong&gt; My natural curiosity helps with this, but my PhD journey really honed this skill.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building (online) communities.&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve been bringing people together online accidentally for as long as I can remember, intentionally for a decade, and in partnership with rigorous research for the past five years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fostering agency.&lt;/strong&gt; My first role as a leader is to affirm and strengthen the &lt;em&gt;agency&lt;/em&gt; of everyone around me. I invite them to co-create with me, I help them self-reflect, and I guide them toward asking better questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-second-four&#34;&gt;A second four:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing compelling arguments.&lt;/strong&gt; Another skill greatly refined by my PhD program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project management.&lt;/strong&gt; This stems back to an innate need to order the world around me and a practiced attention to detail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public speaking.&lt;/strong&gt; This has come from many years of practice and literally hundreds of public speaking engagements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data science.&lt;/strong&gt; I am largely self-taught, partnered with Coursera courses and generous research collaborators. I have worked through big data methods on numerous projects now. I specialize in R.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-experiences&#34;&gt;My Experiences&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;founder&#34;&gt;Founder&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some years ago I was the Founding National Director of a startup called Ministry in Digital Spaces. Simply put, I was aiming to define a new way to be church. We were tasked with building online communities of undergraduate students from across the United States. So, I did my homework. I called more than a hundred leaders in tech. I hosted a half dozen think tanks with industry experts. I went to events like Game Developers Conference (GDC) in 2016 to join and learn from conversations about online communities. I formed an advisory board, hired a team, recruited volunteers, and launched more than 50 pilot projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We built what we set out to build, but our funding was cut. I grew frustrated with the organizational mindset and decided to double down on learning more, choosing in 2017 to focus full-time on pursuing a PhD to better understand online communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;researcher&#34;&gt;Researcher&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My research investigates the networked learning made possible by the novel social and environmental conditions afforded by the Internet. Specifically, I explore how social media platforms support online learning communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my dissertation, I have focused on new teachers during their transition from preparation to practice. New teachers navigate an “edu-verse” made up undergraduate preparation programs, school of employment, district, family and friends, and social media. New teachers today are figuring out what and how to teach while juggling many voices and seeking support from many quarters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve also worked on dozens of other research projects, publishing this work in peer-reviewed journal articles and conference papers. I’ve frequently presented my research to audiences of experts and facilitated workshops on the methods I use. I also teach educational professionals how to teach online and thoughtfully use technology in their teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;executive-coach&#34;&gt;Executive Coach&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I entered the final stages of writing my dissertation, and as the U.S. struggled through dual pandemics of COVID-19 and racism, an old friend from my Ministry in Digital Spaces advisory board called me. He asked me to coach him as he tried to build and scale the organization Black in Gaming. I’ve since helped him, and the rest of the Executive Team, clarify the purpose and goals of the organization, make decisions about bringing the right people into the team, onboard a dozen new leaders, and accomplish all this during a pandemic with a team geographically dispersed across the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-interests&#34;&gt;My Interests&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put it simply: when it comes to what&amp;rsquo;s next, I’m open. By this, I mean both that I’m &lt;strong&gt;curious&lt;/strong&gt; (generally), and I’m currently &lt;strong&gt;looking for a job&lt;/strong&gt; (specifically). There are three things I’d like to make sure I’m doing in this next adventure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leading a community.&lt;/strong&gt; This could involve teaching a class, supervising a lab or team, or building an organization from the ground up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Producing generalizable knowledge.&lt;/strong&gt; I don&amp;rsquo;t want to just solve problems for myself or my team. I want share what we learn in the process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analyzing big data.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve worked hard to develop technical skills, and I love putting these mental muscles to work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diversity Statement</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/diversity-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/diversity-statement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Becoming Qualitative Researchers: An Introduction&lt;/em&gt; (2016), Corrine Glesne argued that to establish the trustworthiness of qualitative research, a researcher must reflect on their &lt;strong&gt;positionality&lt;/strong&gt;, answering, “Why do I notice what I notice?” (p. 153).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am writing this diversity statement as a white, cisgender, heterosexual, American-born man. My parents, grandparents, and great grandparents all received university degrees. It was always assumed that I would pursue an undergraduate degree, and my decisions to later pursue a Master’s degree and a Ph.D. were fully supported by my family. In addition, I experienced adolescence at the same time the Internet went mainstream; I spent my teenage years in chatrooms and have generally had positive online interactions. As a white, straight, cisgender man, I can participate on social media with little risk of being the target of harassment. This is the place from which I write, teach, and research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2012, novelist John Scalzi wrote a blog post titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://whatever.scalzi.com/2012/05/15/straight-white-male-the-lowest-difficulty-setting-there-is/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Straight White Male: The Lowest Difficulty Setting There Is&lt;/a&gt;. This description has resonated with me. It situates any difficulties I have had in a position relative to other experiences, stories, and identities that are generally, systemically more challenging. For instance, few would describe their experiences during the COVID-19 pandemic and American racism pandemic of 2020 as easy. It has been hard for anyone to be productive this year. But, as a white, cisgender, heterosexual man, videos of George Floyd’s and other unarmed Black men’s murders by police inflict less trauma on me than my Black friends and colleagues. News of recent Supreme Court cases on LGBTQ employment rights have come as a relief to me, but not at an existential level. I care about these issues personally and professionally, but the summative effect is less wearying to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these things mean that although I am not guaranteed to “win” this game of life, the degree of difficulty I live and work with is substantially lower than my colleagues and friends who have had various aspects of their identity minoritized and marginalized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My beliefs related to diversity, inclusion, and equity can be conceptualized as behavioral roles: that of learner, mentor, and advocate. Furthermore, I can speak to these three roles at different levels of action: values, experiences, and commitments. I hold values, I have been shaped by experiences, and I will act out commitments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;values&#34;&gt;Values&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, I recognize, and I value, that I am a &lt;strong&gt;learner&lt;/strong&gt;. I am still on a journey, and this is a good and important place to be. My experiences and my identity are steeped in privilege. Even with a lifetime of intentional effort, I will need to continue to actively deconstruct and seek understanding of the ways I hold power and benefit from inequity, especially white supremacy and misogyny. As I continue to learn, I believe I can benefit others by being a &lt;strong&gt;mentor&lt;/strong&gt;, especially to white men. I do not presume to have answers or the ability to save anyone, but I also look for opportunities to be an &lt;strong&gt;advocate&lt;/strong&gt; on behalf of Black, Indigenous, and people of color (BIPOC). I refer back to being a learner here, starting by asking what is needed and what I can do to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;experiences&#34;&gt;Experiences&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have been a learner.&lt;/strong&gt; I grew up in a rural area in the mountains of Virginia. My graduating class in high school was 100% white. For my undergraduate degree, I went to a very white, elite, small, private, liberal arts college. I had next to no understanding of sexual diversity or neurodiversity. Despite not knowing what I did not know, I was curious. One value my family instilled in me was empathy, a deep interest in understanding what it would be like to walk in another person’s shoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This led me to spend two of my undergraduate summers living in a low-income urban U.S. neighborhood, whose residents were largely Puerto Rican and African American. I tutored middle- and high-school-aged students through an all-day camp in a community center. Those summers sparked an interest in sociology, and I added a double major late in my undergraduate years to formally study race and ethnicity. My co-advisors were Barbadian and Indian, and they pushed me to examine my privilege as a white American and as a man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I graduated, I moved back to the urban neighborhood where I had spent those two summers, and I lived there for eight years. I continued to learn from my neighbors. My mentor, and close friend, was an African American garbage collector who had lived in the neighborhood for nearly 70 years. He taught me about home ownership and systemic injustice in our city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years after I finished my undergraduate degree, I spent a summer living in a squatter community in Manila, learning about unjust power systems in the Filipino context as well as grassroots community-organizing efforts. I still get updates from friends in Manila, which put into perspective our current pandemic-related hardships here in the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have been a mentor.&lt;/strong&gt; For five summers, I invited undergraduate students to participate in the same program that was so transformative in my life. I hosted these students as they lived, worked, and learned in my neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my doctoral program, because I moved into academia after a decade in management in my former career, I have collaborated with a number of less experienced colleagues. Two women of color have been interested in the computational methods I use in my work, and I have offered as much time as possible to help them develop their own skills in programming in R.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have been an advocate.&lt;/strong&gt; In my previous career, I once set out to create “the most diverse tech team in America.” I am a bit embarrassed in retrospect at how narrow my conception of diversity was back then. Still, I am grateful for the team that gathered around me. I was able to bring together an incredible group of women and men, Black, Asian, and white. I was never successful in recruiting Latinx or Native people of color to the team. My advocacy for this team often took the form of serving as an umbrella, shielding them from the policies and statements that came down from the senior leadership in our predominantly white institution (PWI). I created space for my team to wield influence beyond just the “diversity work” assumed for people of color in PWIs. However, I failed to make any real, systemic changes in our institution to better support the needs of my team members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the period of heightened activism in the U.S. since June 2020, I have been serving as the Executive Coach for &lt;a href=&#34;https://blackingaming.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Black in Gaming&lt;/a&gt;. This organization seeks to normalize Black cultural identification in the video game industry through education, outreach, representation, and entrepreneurial initiatives. A key partner from my former team is the Executive Director of Black in Gaming, and he reached out to me to help him strategically lead an organizational change process. With Black in Gaming, I have learned and practiced the advocacy I missed in my previous job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://bretsw.com/img/diverse-team.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;diverse team&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;commitments&#34;&gt;Commitments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will be a learner.&lt;/strong&gt; As I serve with Black in Gaming, I continue to learn from the excellent work being done by the executive team. I have found Twitter to be a more effective place for ongoing learning than anywhere else in academia. For years, I have followed the conversations among trans game developers, and this changed my thinking. Through Twitter hashtags like #Educolor and #ClearTheAir, I have been able to identify and follow many Black and Indigenous educators and activists. Every day, they shape my perspective and push my thinking. I do not post my own content very often on social media, but I listen, I pay attention, I learn, and I share the good work others are doing and boost their voices. In June 2020, I heard about an organization called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.academics4blacklives.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Academics for Black Survival and Wellness&lt;/a&gt;, and I have been reading the content they publish. I am committed to continuing to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will be a mentor.&lt;/strong&gt; As I finish my doctoral degree, I am committed to continue my existing mentoring relationships. As I anticipate becoming a tenure-track faculty member and stepping into a place of additional power and privilege, I am committed to mentoring students. I will mentor white students to become anti-racist educators. I will mentor students of color to become academics who are able to write, teach, and research as an expression of their full identities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will be an advocate.&lt;/strong&gt; As I continue on my learning trajectory, from my previous career to serving with Black in Gaming to starting a faculty position, I am committed to continue developing as an advocate for minoritized students. Black in Gaming works to normalize Black cultural identification in the video game industry. I am committed to work toward the normalization of Black and Indigenous cultural identification in academia. I will work toward promoting systemic change to decrease the baseline degree of difficulty experienced by these students and colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I end with a few final, specific commitments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will not assign all-male or all-white readings. I will bring diverse voices and methods into the classroom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will not participate in any all-male panels. Pledges of this kind have gained attention on social media, and McCartney (2019) made a scholarly case in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://science.sciencemag.org/content/364/6444/967.6&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will combat anti-Black racism as it manifests in academia and our communities, as I pledged by signing the call to action from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.academics4blacklives.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Academics for Black Survival and Wellness&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will acknowledge and seek to honor those who have come before me by remembering and including &lt;a href=&#34;http://landacknowledgements.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;land acknowledgements&lt;/a&gt;. This is a fitting way to end this diversity statement:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I Honor Native Land:&lt;/strong&gt; I have learned from the faculty at Michigan State University in East Lansing MI, built on the traditional land of the Peoria, Anishinabewaki, Odawa, and Sauk Peoples, and I have lived and completed my graduate school work in Lancaster County PA, on the traditional land of the Susquehannock People. This acknowledgement demonstrates a commitment to continue the process of working to dismantle the ongoing legacies of settler colonialism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Statement</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/research-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/research-statement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://bretsw.com/img/networked-learning.png&#34; alt=&#34;networked learning&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;research-agenda&#34;&gt;Research Agenda&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I study online learning environments. I research &lt;em&gt;networked learning&lt;/em&gt; at the intersection of educational psychology, instructional technology, and information science. My scholarship investigates the networked learning made possible by the novel social and environmental conditions afforded by the Internet. Specifically, I explore how social media platforms support online learning communities. In various projects, I have framed networked learning in terms of &lt;em&gt;self-directed learning&lt;/em&gt; (i.e., an agentic perspective on socio-cognitive processes), &lt;em&gt;affinity spaces&lt;/em&gt; (i.e., learning environments defined by mutual interests), &lt;em&gt;communities of practice&lt;/em&gt; (i.e., apprenticeship groups), and &lt;em&gt;professional learning networks&lt;/em&gt; (i.e., resources passed between interpersonal connections). I use diverse research methods, from interviews to collecting digital traces of online activity and interactions, such as millions of tweets or Reddit posts. I analyze these data with innovative computational methods including social network analysis, natural language processing, and machine learning classification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focused study of networked learning is important because people rarely learn alone, and the ways in which people can connect and interact continue to expand rapidly with developments in novel online learning environments. Learners today, whether K-12 students, new teachers, or other professionals, exercise agency by seeking advice and resources from far more sources today than ever before as they navigate the affordances of the current social media landscape. My research advances our understanding by more fully attending to both the complex nature of this new reality (e.g., emerging features of social media platforms) as well as the needs of participants in online learning environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my present work, I examine how informal, online learning environments accessed through social media (e.g., Facebook Groups, Twitter, Instagram) shape new teachers’ professional practice in formal K-12 settings. Findings from this study advance understanding of the possibilities and tensions related to seeking resources and collaboration online. In related, ongoing research projects, I investigate how affordances of the social media platforms Twitter and Reddit support distinctive learning environments. For instance, Reddit structures discussion forums into distinct, moderated subreddits by topic, and users’ identities are typically anonymous. This may create more honest and open learning spaces, relatively free from social hierarchy and lacking much of the self-promotion common in education-related Twitter hashtags. Twitter, on the other hand, provides minimal structure to interactions, although users combine hashtags and reply threads to self-organize conversations. Twitter supports learning spaces where questions can be asked and answered quickly, with potentially large and active audiences. Despite these differences, Reddit and Twitter both support online learning environments where participants can develop, test, and refine their knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next five years, I will build on these streams of research in ways that connect to and extend my established research agenda and publication record. I will continue to explore how informal, online learning environments influence formal, face-to-face educational settings. I will investigate how features of under-researched social media platforms (e.g., Instagram, TeachersPayTeachers) are related to the nature of participants’ interactions and subsequent learning. I will further investigate issues of equity, inclusion, and diversity in social media research and practice. These issues are of critical importance because not everyone experiences public online interactions in the same way. That is, although social media provide new avenues for learning, they also pose new risks by asking participants to learn “out in the open.” This means a potential to subject learners, particularly those from marginalized groups, to harassment and blurred lines between personal and professional contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://bretsw.com/img/online-communities.png&#34; alt=&#34;online communities&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;example-of-networked-learning-research&#34;&gt;Example of Networked Learning Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a specific example of a research project investigating networked learning, my dissertation, &lt;em&gt;Into the Edu-verse: New Teachers Seeking Induction Support on Social Media&lt;/em&gt;, explored the numerous challenges that new teachers face during their transition from preparation to practice (i.e., their induction period) and the supports they seek during this time. New teachers seek support from a variety of sources during induction. However, the teacher induction literature has reported a “two worlds pitfall” (Feiman-Nemser &amp;amp; Buchmann, 1985) caused by conflicting messages from the academic world of the preparation program and the practical world of the professional teaching context. New teachers enter their schools of employment with notions of teaching that are not shared—or in some instances, are even actively discouraged—by more experienced colleagues and administrators in that school setting. New teachers must then try to navigate and reconcile conflicting messages to decide how they will enact educational practice. Often, contextual pressure to adapt to the employment environment means that worthwhile academic notions of education from preparation programs are abandoned by new teachers (Feiman-Nemser &amp;amp; Buchmann, 1985).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further complicating teacher induction is an emerging reality where new teachers are no longer seeking help with their profession from just two worlds but a universe of many worlds, an &lt;em&gt;edu-verse&lt;/em&gt;. Social media, a set of participatory practices for using media socially and publicly (Humphreys, 2016), have created additional opportunities for teachers’ self-directed professional learning. Although prior research has discussed challenges posed by teachers’ use of social media for such purposes (e.g., Carpenter &amp;amp; Harvey, 2019), this body of research has rarely focused on the particular challenges experienced by new teachers. For instance, with numerous modalities now available for finding induction support, new teachers may have to navigate conflicting messages about what and how to teach from their preparation program, local employment context, and social media networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this study is to explore what supports for professional learning new teachers seek during induction and how they use social media with the intention of seeking these supports. This research purpose fills a gap between the teacher induction literature, which does not fully consider recent technological advancements, and the social media literature, which does not take into account the needs of new teachers. It is likely that new teachers are seeking support for induction needs from far more sources today than have been previously studied. Supports from and through social media should be specifically considered. In addition, the intense professional and personal dissonance that comes with moving from learning about teaching to actually practicing teaching suggests the challenges and needs of new teachers are likely far more complicated than have been accounted for by research on teachers’ uses of social media generally. From a practical perspective, it is important to explore and understand this gap because new teachers are already experiencing and navigating a new professional reality—a rapidly expanding edu-verse created by the current social media landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Findings from my dissertation deepen understanding of the possibilities and tensions created by new teachers’ use of social media. This study contributes to the field’s ongoing examination of online learning environments, learning in informal settings, and online interactions. I chose an exploratory study for my dissertation because of the new avenues it would open for future research. For instance, I learned that new teachers frequently depend on TeachersPayTeachers for ideas and lesson plans to get them through their first several years but have mixed feelings about the overwhelming number and questionable quality of resources.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Statement</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/teaching-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/teaching-statement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://bretsw.com/img/bretsw-pic3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bret&amp;amp;rsquo;s teaching&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;teaching-philosophy&#34;&gt;Teaching Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My teaching philosophy is shaped by two primary principles. These principles are related to networked learning, a self-directed and social approach to learning. My first role as an educator is to affirm and strengthen students’ &lt;em&gt;agency&lt;/em&gt;. I invite them to co-create their learning experiences, help them self-reflect, and guide them toward asking better questions. Second, I strive to model, and invite students to practice, the principles of &lt;em&gt;open science&lt;/em&gt;. By this, I mean that students learn “out in the open,” sharing both their processes and products to create opportunities for feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I teach toward these principles through several strategies. First, I create a structured plan for my teaching, giving careful thought to overall course organization and flow. I weave a common thread through the course. That is, I offer variety in specific learning tasks but maintain consistency across modules to reduce cognitive load. Second, I assign students meaningful work. That is, I encourage students to connect assignments to real problems they face. For graduate students, this means applying course concepts to tackle thorny problems in their professional context; for undergraduates, this means anticipating their future work. At the start of each semester, I tell students that if they cannot figure out how an assignment will be useful to their professional context and practice, we will work together to adapt the assignment so that it will. Third, I emphasize formative assessment by giving feedback that is timely, thorough, incisive, and kind. I give feedback through various modalities, including video chats, emails, screencast recordings, and comments in documents. In addition to my instructor feedback, I facilitate multidirectional feedback in the form of self-reflection and peer review. Third, building on formative assessments, nearly all the assignments I give are iterative in nature. I design courses around a semester-long project, with regular assignments that help students progress incrementally toward their final product. I emphasize that this process is not linear, but cyclical and responsive to feedback. Students complete work, but then revisit and improve. Fourth, I invite students to practice social scholarship (see my 2019 work with Greenhow and Gleason, published in British Journal of Educational Technology) by tweeting questions and posting work publicly on a blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a specific example, in a Master’s course called &lt;em&gt;Learning Technology by Design&lt;/em&gt;, students develop a problem-of-practice project (i.e., their semester-long task) rooted in their own professional context. Students learn the theory and applications of design thinking by moving their problem-of-practice through one full cycle of a design process, which I draw from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dschool.stanford.edu/resources/design-thinking-bootleg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Stanford d.school model&lt;/a&gt;: understand the audience, define the problem, ideate (i.e., brainstorm and incubate ideas), prototype, test, and iterate. At each stage, I give substantial, formative feedback through text comments on work documents. In addition, I assign students to “design teams,” where they reflect with teammates on course materials, ask questions, pitch their in-process problem-of-practice progress, and give peer feedback regularly through frequent, brief, asynchronous video posts on Flipgrid. Completed assignments take the form of typed documents, handwritten notes, sketches, and video—all of which are compiled into a design report at the end of the semester.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My teaching has been affirmed in a variety of ways. The program coordinators of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://education.msu.edu/cepse/maet/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;M.A. in Educational Technology&lt;/a&gt; program at Michigan State University (MSU) invited me to facilitate a workshop for my fellow instructors based on my teaching approach. As a doctoral student, I was invited to teach as lead instructor and simultaneously mentor less experienced graduate assistants, for both undergraduate and Master’s level courses at MSU. I was also invited to redesign and rewrite both undergraduate and Master’s courses at MSU, and I was hired to write a course called The Evolving Landscape of Educational Technology for a new Master’s program at Concordia University. Students have consistently rated my teaching between “Superior” and “Above Average.” More importantly, students have frequently commented in course evaluations how they appreciate the feedback I give them, how I organize courses, and my kindness and enthusiasm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In sum, I have substantial teaching and course design experience at the university level on a range of topics. I have taught each of the courses in Michigan State University’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://education.msu.edu/academics/graduate-specializations-certificates/#online-teaching-learning&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Graduate Certificate in Online Teaching and Learning&lt;/a&gt;. I am prepared to teach courses, both online and face-to-face, at the doctoral, Master’s and undergraduate levels. I look forward to continuing to teach in ways that increase students’ agency and facilitate their practice of open science principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;student-feedback&#34;&gt;Student Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cannot tell you how much I appreciate how helpful and understanding you have been all semester. Your approach to teaching is heartwarming and gives me hope for higher education. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if you plan on going into a faculty position somewhere after your PhD, but if you do, your students will be very rewarded by your style and knowledge. It is not always a guarantee to have a great instructor, but when you do, you remember their name and refer back to the work you did with them because the learning experience was memorable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe our instructor, Bret, was one of the most supportive instructors I have ever had. He helped me really grasp formative assessments, a concept I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really familiar with, and provided me with extensive feedback. With Bret&amp;rsquo;s guidance, I felt like I was constantly improving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though this was an online course, Bret was the best professor that I have had at MSU thus far. His class was extremely organized and easy to follow, he was very quick to respond to emails or any questions that I have. He returned grades quickly and always took time to give meaningful feedback for weekly assignments. He even commented on our discussion posts! I was so impressed with this course and this professor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bret was amazing and I am so happy to have had him as my instructor. This is my first semester of grad school and to know that my instructor was so cool, it gives me hope that my other instructors will be just as cool throughout my program. Bret, thank you for everything that you&amp;rsquo;ve done for me throughout the semester. I appreciate it all of your feedback that you gave and I am happy that you pushed me to go beyond my limit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bret was always understanding, easy to contact, fast to reply and concerned about student&amp;rsquo;s performance. I was really impressed with the way he reached out and communicated with me, I was able to &amp;lsquo;know&amp;rsquo; my teacher without having to physically meet them. I think that would be really hard for me to do otherwise through an online class but Bret did a great job of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I primarily worked with Bret. He communicated so effectively. He provided clear constructive feedback, was always available when I had questions. He helped me learn based on where I was personally, and not assuming I would be an expert on design. I really felt like I came full circle with a lot of realizations about how this course content can be applied to my real life work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I absolutely loved this course and the professors. This was probably my favorite course in the MAET program. It was wonderfully taught with design thinking in mind which lent itself well to the content being taught. I learn so much in this course. This course completely impacted my classroom teaching. I will be continuing on the project that I started in this course to hopefully make a lasting impact in my classroom. I could not say enough good things about this course. Fantastic setup, wonderful instruction, great feedback, all wonderful!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did my MBA online with a few face-to-face classes. Looking through it all, this is the first online course that I really enjoyed. It was online, but hands on and engaging. The students were free to wander and experiment with topics. The tone was interesting and respectful. This is a practice I intend to emulate going forward with teaching online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was such a super useful course! I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how it could be done, but I think it should be either required, or somehow strongly recommended or marketed to other students. Or at least recommended to students with no previous formal teacher training. I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I almost didn&amp;rsquo;t take this course! That would have been a disaster&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
