<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>New Paper on Bret Staudt Willet, Ph.D.</title>
    <link>https://bretsw.com/tags/new-paper/</link>
    <description>Recent content in New Paper on Bret Staudt Willet, Ph.D.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bretsw.com/tags/new-paper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New paper: Initial discussions of ChatGPT in education-related subreddits</title>
      <link>https://bretsw.com/post/new-paper-chatgpt-reddit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretsw.com/post/new-paper-chatgpt-reddit/</guid>
      
        <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a good bit of good news coming in the next few weeks, and I wanted to kick things off my highlighting a new publication that just came out in the Journal of Research on Technology in Education: &amp;ldquo;Initial discussions of ChatGPT in education-related subreddits&amp;rdquo; (DOI:10.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New paper: Early career teachers’ expansion of professional learning networks with social media</title>
      <link>https://bretsw.com/post/new-paper-early-career-teachers-pln/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretsw.com/post/new-paper-early-career-teachers-pln/</guid>
      
        <description>Background I recently had an article titled &amp;ldquo;Early career teachers’ expansion of professional learning networks with social media&amp;rdquo; published in the journal Professional Development in Education (DOI:10.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New paper: Affinity and anonymity benefitting early career teachers in the r/Teachers subreddit</title>
      <link>https://bretsw.com/post/new-paper-affinity-anonymity-reddit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretsw.com/post/new-paper-affinity-anonymity-reddit/</guid>
      
        <description>Background My first Ph.D. student, Hunhui Na, and I recently co-authored an article titled &amp;ldquo;Affinity and anonymity benefitting early career teachers in the r/Teachers subreddit&amp;rdquo; in the Journal of Research on Technology in Education (DOI:10.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New paper: Balancing open science and privacy in the context of learning analytics</title>
      <link>https://bretsw.com/post/new-paper-balancing-open-science-and-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretsw.com/post/new-paper-balancing-open-science-and-privacy/</guid>
      
        <description>Background I recently co-authored (with Josh Rosenberg a response to a valuable paper by Ifenthaler and Schumacher (2016) as a part of a special issue of Educational Technology Research &amp;amp; Development on &amp;ldquo;Shifting to Digital&amp;rdquo; in light of the COVID-19 pandemic.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>